Since its formation. the Earth
has experienced five mass extinctions.
The sixth is just beginning.
CARIBBEAN SEA
off the coast of Puerto Rico
Eating that crap again?
Gimme a break. Give it back.
Eat some fruit.
Back off.
When you unlock the reel.
you have to make sure
you hold the line
with one finger.
like this. okay?
Now you can open it.
Now you're ready to cast it.
And while you cast it.
you need to release
the line. okay?
Now you try.
-Okay.
-Okay?
-Um--
-You remember?
I think so. sir.
Very well.
You unlocked the reel
and now you're ready to cast it.
Nice! Great!
Yankee overboard.
-It's fighting!
-Really?
Yeah. sure. Okay.
give it some slack.
Tom!
Help!
Dad.
-Dad!
-Julia!
Dad. where are you? I need help!
Help me!
Julia!
Fuck!
Cassie! Hey! Cassie!
Cassie! Come in! I need you!
-What?
-Mom needs help! Come in!
What happened?
Grab onto something.
Wait.
I can go. Dad.
You just need to stop the boat.
I can go. I've got my swimsuit.
I can just jump
-and I can--
-You're staying here!
-Dad! Dad!
-Stay here and keep her steady.
-I can go and help her!
-You stay here
and keep her steady!
I got you.
I got you. Don't worry.
Dad! Go to the back!
We're gonna go to the back
and we're gonna help you!
Dad!
-Okay.
-Come here!
You're almost there! Mom!
-Mom. I've got you.
I've got you.
-You're okay.
I don't know what happened.
I got caught in a current.
I couldn't do anything. I--
I-- I really thought
I wasn't gonna make it.
Now listen. everyone.
I've already told you.
but let me say this again.
When you go swimming.
you tell the others first.
Okay?
Ben?
-Yeah.
-And you never
swim away from the boat.
Is that clear? Cassie?
What. you really think
I'm gonna go and. like...
...swim
in the middle of the ocean?
This is serious.
I'm not kidding.
We don't even know
what's down there.
Hmmm?
Aye. aye. Captain.
What?
I was thinking...
...how lucky I am
to have such a beautiful wife.
Are you saying that
because I almost drowned?
How about I lock in the kids?
Silly.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday. dear Ben ♪
♪ And many more ♪
Hey. my love.
-Happy birthday. kiddo.
-Dad. please! Stop it.
I'm 13 now.
I'm not your kiddo anymore.
You'll always be my kiddo.
Oh. come on.
just blow out the candles.
-You made a wish?
-Sure. I did.
-Bravo!
Bravo!
Here we go.
It's exactly the one I wanted!
And it's not just
only for gaming. okay?
-It's beautiful. isn't it?
-Yeah. it's really cool.
-And this one.
-Oh. my gosh.
-Even you?
-Yeah.
Well. that's not that different
from your actual face.
but you know. whatever.
Show. show.
-Oh. my God.
-Mm.
And another one.
I hope you like it.
It's Dominican.
I love it!
-You see?
-Mm.
A good luck charm
to ward off evil spirits.
I mean. are you sure though?
'Cause Cassie's
still right here.
-Uh-huh.
-Stop that! Okay.
Ins-- instead of saying
stupid stuff. go on.
let's take a picture.
-Okay. get into position.
-Okay. okay. okay. one second.
-You guys too!
-Obviously. Yeah. move.
Just go there.
-It's got the timer?
-Yeah.
Okay. get ready. Five. four...
Three. two. one.
-Cheese!
-Okay. that one's gonna be good.
-Okay.
-Can I have some cake?
-You are a bottomless pit.
Oh. wait. Miami's calling.
-Get out. Damn.
-It's gonna be Adam.
-Hey. everyone.
-Hey.
-How you doing. guys?
-Look.
-It's Ben's birthday.
-Hi. Adam.
Hi. Adam. How are you?
-Hi.
-Okay. hold on.
I'm gonna get some privacy.
Stop. Stop it.
-Seriously. stop!
-Where are you going?
You're walking
so long right now.
It's impossible to get
some privacy over here.
Okay. I'm back.
-So. how's the cruise going?
-Uh. well.
my mom almost
drowned this morning.
but apart from that.
it's actually pretty boring.
-Boring. you said?
-Yeah.
I honestly
can't wait to see you.
Yeah. me too.
Will you be here on Saturday?
-Yeah.
-It's going to be a great party.
It would be a shame
if you weren't there.
-But I guess I'll have
to call Naomi or something.
-Very funny.
-Seriously. Adam.
don't you dare--
Are you seeing this right now?
This is crazy.
-I've never seen
clouds like that.
-Yeah.
Yeah. me neither.
Adam.
Shit! What--
Dad! Dad!
So soon?
We lost the connection.
There were really weird clouds
in the sky.
and then we just got cut off
-and I can't reach him anymore.
-Listen.
We've got to be
at least five miles away
from the coast of Cuba.
You will try again later. Ben?
It's whales.
You know. whales follow
the Earth's magnetic field.
Well. sometimes storms
can cause abnormalities.
And so. the whales head in
towards the coast.
convinced they're actually
headed along it.
Nothing weird about that.
-Ben. you good?
-Yeah.
-Okay. Cassie?
-Yes.
What was that?
Are you sure
you wanna go down there?
Don't worry. I just need
to take a look at the shafts
and the propellers.
Be careful.
Dad.
-Oh. shit!
-Are you okay?
Hold on.
Let me see.
I felt something behind me.
And when I turned around.
I cut myself in the propeller.
Hold still.
Wha-- what was it?
Like a sh-- a shark?
I don't know. It was big.
It was really big.
How bad is it?
Well. the shafts are bent.
And one of the propellers
is shot.
-Can you fix them?
-No way.
-We need to call for help.
-Best holiday ever.
Well. yes. I'm sorry.
If you keep moving. I can't do it.
Dad?
Orca. Orca. engine failure.
Pan-pan. pan-pan. pan-pan.
This is motor yacht Orca.
Orca. Orca. Coordinates--
Engine failure. coordinates.
two-zero degrees.
three-zero minutes north...
Fucking hell!
...zero-zero minutes west.
Four passengers on board.
Pan-pan.
Ben. seriously? We're in deep shit here!
This is motor yacht Orca. Orca.
Engine failure.
Coordinates. two-zero degrees.
three-zero minutes north.
Zero-five forward degrees.
zero-zero minutes west.
Engine failure.
Coordinates...
-...zero minutes west.
-Shit!
Four passengers on board.
Pan-pan. pan-pan. pan-pan.
What is that?
I don't know. Check by yourself.
This is motor yacht...
Beat it.
Get off my bed. Move!
Fucking move!
It's gross.
You got crumbs everywhere.
-...four passengers. over.
-Fucking shit!
Pan-pan. pan-pan. This is
motor yacht Orca calling.
Orca! Oscar. Romeo.
Charlie. Alpha.
Anyone hear me? Over.
Oh. fucking shit!
Well. we have
26 gallons of water.
-And food for at least
four days. We'll be fine.
-How can you be so sure?
Well. I'm not sure!
But we're on a shipping route.
There's no way
we won't see anyone.
What the fuck?
You see that?
Dad. what is that?
I've no idea.
-Holy shit!
-Whoa!
Let's have a look from up there.
-Dad. watch out!
-Whoa!
We need to move!
Dad. Dad. a third one! Up there!
Those are not meteorites.
They're satellites.
Da-- Dad. Dad. Dad.
-Wha--
-Th-- there's smoke there.
There's nothing we can do.
Get inside. everyone.
Ben!
-Dad. Ben's hurt. Ben's hurt.
-Come on.
Sit down. okay?
-Are you okay? All right.
-Yeah. I'm okay.
Watch out!
...okay. sit down.
Mom...
This is motor yacht Orca.
Oscar. Romeo. Charlie. Alpha.
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday!
Can you hear me? Anyone? Over!
Mayday! Mayday!
Help! Mayday! Mayday!
Mayday. May--
mayday. mayday. mayday!
This is the Orca!
Oscar. Romeo. Charlie. Alpha.
We're in a storm! We need help!
Ben!
Kids?
What?
Ben!
Still nothing.
-Dad. Wha--
-Mm?
What are we going to do?
There must be other survivors.
We need to contact them.
I'm not worried.
You always find a solution.
You're right. Ben.
Every problem has a solution.
This is weird.
This is simply not possible!
Well. north is not
where it should be.
North indicates south
and south indicates north.
As if the poles reversed.
-Is that even possible?
-Last time it happened
was more than 700.000 years ago.
Where's the sea?
It seems it's
where it shouldn't be.
Wait.
Wait. so does that mean
that the sea just went--
Maybe to where the land was.
So that would mean
that... Adam...
No. no. no. no.
no. no... it can't be true.
Cassie.
...no. no. no. no. no. no.
that doesn't make
any sense. right?
That doesn't make any sense.
the poles cannot
just reverse like that.
-Wait. We need to--
-It doesn't make any sense.
It's ridiculous!
We don't know anything for sure.
-Cassie. please!
-Cassie. Cassie!
Honey...
We don't know for sure.
Don't go imagining the worst.
Come on.
Go away.
Go away. will you!
Mom! Dad!
Where is he?
It's for the other survivors!
They'll see it from far away!
See? I can think
of good solutions too.
It's working now. Julia.
It just needed more power.
Mayday. Mayday. Mayday.
This is the Orca motor yacht.
Oscar. Romeo. Charlie. Alpha.
The ocean has gone.
Four passengers.
Over.
Mayday.
This is Nao.
Captain of the Shanghai 6500.
-Over.
-Hey! Hi.
Hi. I'm Tom.
So happy to finally
hear someone.
Do you have
any idea what happened?
Reverse of the magnetic poles.
We were deep diving
when the ocean retreated
and submerged the mainlands.
-How far?
-Impossible to say as it stands.
I can't believe it.
The conspiracy theory nuts
were right.
Maybe the earth has decided
to eliminate the men
before they destroy it.
Well. you could be right.
Have you come into contact
with any other survivors?
No. Most communication systems
are down.
Anyway. there are
systemic movements
which indicate that the poles
are going to reverse again
-and the sea could return.
-When?
According to my instruments.
no more than a week.
This is going to be
really violent.
Try to climb
as high as possible.
We gotta go. Pack up your stuff.
Ben. move.
Come on. let's go.
Come with me.
-How many people
can you take on board?
The Shanghai is
a scientific bathyscaphe.
The capacity is for three.
My partner didn't have
his safety harness.
He did not survive.
We're sorry for your loss.
So you can take our kids?
Please. y-- you can trust us.
We really just want
to save our children.
Look. I'm an oceanographer
from the University of Miami.
My wife's a doctor.
You can really--
We're just asking you
to save our children. please.
18.30 north. 83.00 west.
Okay.
According to your coordinates.
you're two or three days away.
I will stay connected
on channel 16.
Don't worry.
Only the children.
Good luck.
We're getting
a good night's sleep.
And we're leaving tomorrow
early in the morning. okay?
We have a good chance
of making it there
before the ocean comes back.
Okay.
We are gonna make this.
And I'll be with you.
Okay? Let's prepare the kids.
I'm so glad to finally
run into someone.
I'm Tom.
Are you hurt?
My wife's a doctor
if you need any help.
Are you sure you're okay?
Hey!
Stop! Stop!
Stop it! Stop!
Cassie!
Mom!
What's going on?
Hide back there!
Mom?
There! Move it!
Get in.
Fast! Come on!
If it's not me. the flare's loaded.
Shoot!
Get it? Shoot if it's not me.
Shoot.
Shoot!
Get out!
Get out.
Mom. what the hell are you doing?
Forget the supplies!
Hurry!
Forget the bags!
Come on. Dad. Please!
Please. Dad.
Come on.
Let's go!
Dad!
Drink. A few sips.
You think he saw the balloons?
What?
The psycho.
You think he saw the balloons?
Stop.
Don't say that.
Don't blame yourself.
There was no way of knowing.
Don't blame yourself. okay?
It's not your fault. Got it?
It's not your fault.
I'll do all I can to protect you.
I won't let anyone hurt you.
No one.
What?
Come on!
Go!
Keep going!
What's wrong?
Dehydration. You need fluids.
Hold on.
Who the hell did this?
Drink what's left.
I think I left it unscrewed.
Shit. Cassie. it's empty!
It wasn't on purpose.
How do we survive without water?
Don't yell at me. Back off.
It's not like we won't die anyway.
-Don't say that!
-Why? We're gonna croak.
It's the truth!
You think you can save us
but you can't!
Nobody can save us.
We're gonna croak here.
Dad got slaughtered by a freak.
and you're obsessed about a bottle.
A fucking bottle!
Enough!
Shut up. that's enough!
Shut up!
Go right.
Thanks.
Try to get some sleep.
I can't believe he's gone forever.
I feel like...
I've fallen off a cliff.
I know.
Tell me the story of how you met again.
The first time I saw him.
I was 22.
I was training
at the hospital in Nice.
And one morning...
a German was brought in
after a diving accident.
What was he doing?
Research for his thesis
on red gorgonians dying out
in the Mediterranean.
On what?
They look like coral.
Anyway. he'd had a...
decompression issue on a dive.
He spent three days
in a hyperbaric chamber.
There are better first meetings.
As soon as he got out.
he started hitting on me.
It worked?
Not right away.
I set him straight.
As his doctor.
As if that would stop him.
Two days later.
outside the hospital.
he was waiting with flowers.
Old school.
We spent a whole week together.
It was...
He had to go back to Germany.
I thought...
I'd never see him again.
And then?
Six months later. he...
He was there.
outside the hospital.
And...
he declared his undying love.
With a poem by Victor Hugo.
"It's enough for you to fly away.
"For me to fly too."
Then.
he explained
he'd got his degree
and been offered a job in Miami.
And he'd only accept it
if I agreed to go with him.
Not an easy decision.
To practice in the USA.
I had to requalify.
You know what he said?
Every problem has a solution.
What could have done this?
Whatever it was. it's not human.
So there's something out there
even nastier than this wacko.
Come on.
Let's go.
Wait!
Where you going?
Wait for us.
Get out of there right now!
Don't!
Are you nuts? You'll get sick!
Kids!
We can't stay here.
What's going on?
Move it!
Look!
People.
Let's go.
There's a woman and children!
Forget about it.
Look. behind them!
Help!
-There's more of them. Get inside!
-Help!
Help us!
Help! Help!
-Help! Please. help!
-No!
No!
Open up! Come on!
Open up!
Go on. Cassie. climb up.
Keep going!
C'mon. kids.
Back up.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Mom!
We went for help. There's no one!
Where's Ben?
Where'd you learn to do that?
Cassie. keep watch.
Shit. a radio!
Grab that gun!
Work. dammit.
Channel 16.
Work.
Nao?
Nao. this is Julia. Tom's wife.
Are you there?
Come in. Nao?
Nao. this is Julia. Tom's wife.
Where are you?
I don't really know.
Uh. I lost the nautical chart.
We found a freighter
and containers.
We got attacked by something.
I got attacked last night.
What is this shit?
Arthropods from the abyss.
The sea released them
when it retreated.
The oxygen seems
to drive them crazy.
They have no more food.
They attack to eat.
Life adapts to the environment.
Are there still four of you?
No.
Only three of us are left.
My children and myself.
-Are you there?
-Yes.
Just save
my children. please.
You save my children. okay?
You need to hurry.
According to the movement
of my instrument's recording.
the sea is coming back
faster than expected.
How long?
It's a matter of hours.
Okay. We're leaving right now.
But. uh. I don't know
in which direction.
Just watch in the sky.
Okay. we see you!
Look. over there.
Shit...
That rift.
Let's go.
What's with "save my children" earlier?
Ben. c'mon!
Mom. all good?
Keep going.
Watch out!
Hurry!
Here we go again.
Shit!
Watch out!
Mom?
Climb over!
Hold on. listen to me.
Keep going!
-What?
-Just go!
No!
Keep going. I said!
No. climb over it!
Just go!
Climb over it!
Hurry!
Climb!
Mom. we're not going anywhere.
Come with us. for fuck's sake!
Not without you!
Take Ben and go!
You hear me? Just go!
I'll find you.
I'll find you. Now go!
We're going. Come on!
Careful.
There!
Nao!
Nao! Are you in there?
Oh.
Oh. my God.
It's a matter of minutes.
Get inside. It's over for me.
I'm gonna go and get her.
-I'm gonna go and get her.
-No.
-I have to! I have to. Ben!
-Wait!
Come on.
Grab my hand.
There's room for you.
Climb up. come on.
Give me that.
Inside!
Go on. get in.
C'mon. now!
-Fast!
-Get inside!
Hurry up. Ben!
How does this shut?
Turn it.
We're good.
Push it.
It's coming.
Sit down. Get in your seats!
Fast!
Strap in!
-Fuck it!
-Look...
Cross them in front.
♪ Happy Birthday to-- ♪
Fuck.
SURVIVE